Habad Olad

Hampstead London

www.habadolad.com Github olad.hab@gmail.com 07904087437

PERSONAL STATEMENT:

A qualified tutor and postgraduate researcher with a background in consulting working on the UK's most high-profile infrastructure developments such as High Speed 2 and Heathrow terminal expansion. Skilled in creating positive relationships with customers and stakeholders Experienced in project management, database administration, consulting. Transitioning into a career in Data analysis, having completed a 11 weeks analytics bootcamp, I received expert training in SQL, Python and powerBI. My love of problem solving, playing with data, and uncovering patterns has led me to a career change. So I chose a new career that built digital skills upon my existing analogue abilities.

KEY SKILLS

- Programming: HTML, CSS, javaScript, NodeJs, NextJs, SQL, React,
- Proficiency in Microsoft office suite: Excel, Powerpoint, Access, Outlook etc.
- Project shaping, delivering, analysis and leading experience
- Project management including workshops planning, facilitating, and documenting the output
- Communicating effectively and confidently with both internal staff, external teams and stakeholders
- Consulting and presenting to stakeholders, c-suite and local councils.
- Critical thinking- Analysing and evaluating key information to identify effective solutions, including streamlining processes to increase production line efficiency
- Leadership led numerous teams for group projects for Hs2, Heathrow expansion, .

EXPERIENCE

February 2020 - February 2021 Volunteer- Keats Library, London

- · Teaching young students Microsoft office suites and GCSE studies. Which led to an increase of library usage amongst the younger demographic.
- · Maintained library inventory and conducted periodic audits of the information on file. Help patrons navigate the electronic records and periodicals
- \cdot Create and implement new programs to attract patrons of different demographics. Leading to an increased membership rate at the library of 20%.

<u>December 2018 – February 2020 Postgraduate research adviser – University of London</u>

- \cdot Providing support and offering a quality service to students who require extracurricular help in research methodologies. This led to advisory for 6 postgraduate students in the economics department leading to 8 postdoctoral degrees completed
- \cdot Succeeded in building a bespoke learning and development programme to build students skills and knowledge. This led to a 100% completion rate of student dissertations with 6 out of 8 receiving distinctions with the 2 achieving merits

March 2017 - December 2018 Land Consultant - WSP Global, London

WSP Group PLC, a multidisciplinary consultancy based in London, UK, creating a professional services firm with 15,000 employees working in 300 offices worldwide.

- \cdot Led teams in data interpolation and collection of phases of HS2 accumulating over 300,000 responses and over 300 consultations. The received qualitative feedback indicated that the public were 67% positive in support of the project which allows a compulsory purchase order to occur.
- · Managed the Crossrail 2 workshops and consulting phases of projects which led to a positive 97% public feedback. This includes attending internal and external meetings and liaising with diverse stakeholders.
- \cdot Managing and delivering change or small projects. Systems worked with included Excel, ARC GIS, ARC Maps, database management software.

EDUCATION

2015 – 2016, Imperial College London Merit, Environmental Technology

2011 - 2014, University of Hull Upper second class, Geography BSC

INTERESTS

A new hobby of mine has become blogging. I have recently started a substack micro-blogging website to record my journey to becoming a data analyst. I have recently fallen in love with coding and spend a lot of my spare time on websites such as Datacamp and The Odin Project which allow me to learn and challenge myself with Python.